[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e40", "question": "What's the only consonant sound that can end a word in Japanese?", "answer": "N", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a943", "question": "What does \"Lo Stivale\", the local name for the Italian peninsula, mean in Italian?", "answer": "The boot", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c033", "question": "What is the more common name for serigraphy?", "answer": "Screen printing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58e2f54e2e77afa695b03104", "question": "What is the capital of Maldives?", "answer": "Mal\u00e9", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be70", "question": "What is Michigan Stadium also known as?", "answer": "The Big House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe735c8eec85e375820b251", "question": "Who said, \"A pessimist sees the difficulty in every opportunity; an optimist sees the opportunity in every difficulty.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c15", "question": "Who are the four main characters of the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Stan, Kyle, Cartman and Kenny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895f", "question": "Who murders Nancy in \"Oliver Twist\"?", "answer": "Bill Sikes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339149", "question": "Who wrote the \"Shogun\" series of novels?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3f", "question": "What acoustic track was the only number one hit for 1990s hard-rock band Mr. Big?", "answer": "To Be with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd770e347d002c297e4c3", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Diana?", "answer": "Artemis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73383eec85e375820b222", "question": "What was the code name for the evacuation of Allied soldiers from the beaches of Dunkirk, France?", "answer": "Operation Dynamo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede30d6ce05a3942286dd0", "question": "Who originally sang \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\"?", "answer": "Gene Autry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d80", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Matthew Harrison Brady in the novel \"Inherit the Wind\"?", "answer": "William Jennings Bryan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab1071baab681b0929216b", "question": "Mad Shelia is a Chinese action movie that's heavily influenced by which George Miller-directed blockbuster from 2015?", "answer": "Mad Max: Fury Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b040", "question": "What general commanded the US military operations in the Vietnam War from 1964 to 1968?", "answer": "William Westmoreland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b3", "question": "N2O is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e3f6a85cb9e8bda682136d", "question": "What year did the first commercially produced tea bags appear on the market?", "answer": "1904", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1c", "question": "General John J. Pershing was in command of the American troops during what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af98717aeb0982ee4559551", "question": "What is the famous forced march of the Cherokee from Georgia to Indian Country called?", "answer": "The Trail of Tears", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfbe5e003d27d341092bcd", "question": "What is the only \"road\" in London, England?", "answer": "Goswell Road", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaab", "question": "Ankara is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca9", "question": "Al Pacino's satanic character in \"The Devil's Advocate\" is named for what author?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7505a9e54d890926f702", "question": "What is illegal to eat with a cherry pie in Kansas?", "answer": "Ice cream", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600e0e381d348e9c6eed4815", "question": "How many people (military and civilians) in the Soviet Union died from World War II.", "answer": "Approximately 27 million people died as a result of the war, which represented 15% of the population of the country.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596761662b59efe0e9417ea3", "question": "What country music artist was nicknamed \"Chief\" after his maternal grandfather, who was Chief of Police?", "answer": "Eric Church", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa8ce6ce05a3942286ed7", "question": "Who played the part of Max Cady in the 1991 thriller \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Robert De Niro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d2", "question": "What disease was once nicknamed \"the white plague\"?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24d", "question": "Do sea gulls drink sea water?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d08", "question": "What mythological figure flew too close to the sun, and fell into the sea and drown when the sun melted the wax on his wings?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1e", "question": "If cattle are bovine, what are sheep?", "answer": "Ovine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdd98e347d002c297e4f2", "question": "Who wrote the collection of short stories on which Fiddler on the Roof was based?", "answer": "Sholem Aleichem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c8", "question": "What board game was invented by Charles B. Darrow during the Great Depression?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b667", "question": "What is the total weight of a full standard set of billiards balls, including the cue ball?", "answer": "6 pounds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ebb408d98002fdd633b1", "question": "When was the maiden voyage of the \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594a63192ebb971c1417fb97", "question": "What year did the \"Turbot War\" fishing dispute end?", "answer": "1996", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c009", "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1cf", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Philip Guichet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab58", "question": "Which former Soviet Republic has Tashkent as its capital?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cbcc877e98cb97778a1f", "question": "Thimphu is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e58bfe83fe1f2a824bc0", "question": "Broadway was established in what year in New York?", "answer": "1750", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37f", "question": "A male duck is properly known as what?", "answer": "A drake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e910598d7247dfc0fa00313", "question": "What year was the element Berkelium discovered?", "answer": "1949", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe1", "question": "In what country is the Nobel Peace Prize awarded?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34d", "question": "What is the second largest continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc90", "question": "Who is the only founding member of both the International Surfing and Swimming Halls of Fame?", "answer": "Duke Kahanamoku", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe522a01bf59ab7d2e380e8", "question": "Who did Nicolas Cage marry in 2002?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Presley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc35", "question": "What broadcasting company owns CNN?", "answer": "Time Warner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc4f76ce05a3942286f39", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Girls Just Want to Have Fun\"?", "answer": "Cyndi Lauper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c531", "question": "What is the first element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338996", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Terms of Endearment\" that was later adapted into a 1983 Best Picture film?", "answer": "Larry McMurtry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec260b8dc25ca9e12ef644", "question": "London's Trafalgar Square Christmas tree is traditionally given by which country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339222", "question": "As a child, what did Casper the Friendly Ghost die from?", "answer": "Pneumonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b985", "question": "What name is given to the vertical bar of a window?", "answer": "Mullion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f2", "question": "How many pieces does each player start a game of chess with?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11d", "question": "What word is used for an adult female sheep?", "answer": "Ewe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c8", "question": "What military cemetery is located across the Potomac River from the Lincoln Memorial?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071f1e3745b36be73039e8", "question": "What is the full name of Em Cypress, Dana's sister and reviver, in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Martha Ann Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde4f1fc6c6b019850c9a88", "question": "Who, according to the Bible, led the Israelites into The Promised Land?", "answer": "Joshua", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339337", "question": "How many children did Lucy and Desi have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c447", "question": "How many chromosomes does a turkey have?", "answer": "80", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6007823abd51d85e222ab655", "question": "How did the Mus\u00e9e Picasso in Paris come to own its collection of Picasso's works?", "answer": "Since he left no will, his\u00a0death duties\u00a0to the French state were paid in the form of works from his personal collection.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c288", "question": "What term applies to space devoid of matter?", "answer": "Vacuum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febb0737e83c707845b2104", "question": "Which two gems are different colors of the same mineral?", "answer": "Ruby and sapphire", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc1b36ce05a3942286f13", "question": "In the \"Captain America: The Winter Soldier\" film, who was Winter Soldier?", "answer": "Bucky Barnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73377eec85e375820b221", "question": "What was the name of the antisemitic laws passed in Nazi Germany on September 15, 1935?", "answer": "Nuremberg Law", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf7", "question": "What is the best known artificial international language?", "answer": "Esperanto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a02", "question": "What 1980\u2019s game show often featured contestants asking for \"no Whammys!\"?", "answer": "Press Your Luck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab64", "question": "From what country did the US buy the Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a58a", "question": "The city of Philadelphia is located in which US state?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb2e065ff7d326b622a7b", "question": "Which Apollo space mission put the first men on the moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"War & Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa4736ce05a3942286eb2", "question": "In the original television series \"Hawaii Five-O,\" what was Degective McGarrett's catchphrase?", "answer": "\"Book 'em, Danno!\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b63ee662d71a53651004", "question": "In Herman Melville\u2019s novel \"Moby Dick\", who was the loyal, reasonable first mate?", "answer": "Starbuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015dfddfe83fe1f2a824b82", "question": "When was the first fax machine invented?", "answer": "1840s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bf", "question": "Which actor played the role of Dawson on the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\"?", "answer": "James Van Der Beek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4e", "question": "What late 1970's hit contains the following line \"Ooh, you make my motor run, my motor run\"?", "answer": "My Sharona", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a466", "question": "In what state would you find the Black Rock Desert?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a23", "question": "What name is usually given to Quasimodo who features in a French novel first published in 1831?", "answer": "The Hunchback of Notre Dame", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c382", "question": "What poisonous spider can be identified by a small red hourglass-shaped marking on the underside of its body?", "answer": "Black widow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c355", "question": "What is the shape of the Earth?", "answer": "Oblate spheroid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fb", "question": "In the 1998 movie \"You've Got Mail\", Joe and Kelly are in what business?", "answer": "Book retailing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f86cfe83fe1f2a824c2d", "question": "Passover is celebrated around the same time with a Christian holiday. What Christian holiday is this?", "answer": "Easter Passover is usually celebrated in March or April, which is around the same time Christians also celebrate Easter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ff", "question": "Which US state's official song is \"On the Banks of the Wabash, Far Away\"?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339085", "question": "What is considered as the first daily comic strip in the US?", "answer": "Mutt and Jeff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede5c16ce05a3942286df0", "question": "What is the only product Elvis Presley ever did a live TV commercial for?", "answer": "Southern Maid Donuts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2f", "question": "Which ocean is the region of Melanesia located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b8", "question": "What boxer appeared in the broadway musical \"Buck White\" in 1969?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9e", "question": "What kind of bird is Wallace and Gromit's nemesis, Feathers McGraw?", "answer": "A penguin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd63", "question": "What Indonesian word names the art of successively waxing and dyeing fabric?", "answer": "Batik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d96", "question": "Who replaced Stanley Kubrick on the western film \"One-Eyed Jacks\", making it the only film he ever directed?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133953c", "question": "What soap opera was on air from 1952 until 2009?", "answer": "Guiding Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e7", "question": "What does the acronym \"SCTV\" stand for?", "answer": "Second City Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd3", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Hippomenes also known as?", "answer": "Melanion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b022", "question": "What world leader was Time magazine's \"Man of the Year\" for 1938?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09c", "question": "What wine barrel contains 126 gallons?", "answer": "Pipe or butt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173c3444491cbd7c5a17a4", "question": "What collectively-named languages evolved from Vulgar Latin?", "answer": "Romance or romanic language -- The five most spoken romance languages are Spanish, French, Portuguese, Italian and Romanian.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ed", "question": "What was the name of Dan Ackroyd\u2019s butler in the movie \"Trading Places\"?", "answer": "Coleman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e8", "question": "Greenland is a dependency of what European country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what platoon was Abe Simpson in charge of during WWII?", "answer": "The Flying Hellfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339137", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Apollo?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c24", "question": "In which movie marked the first appearance of Charlie Chaplin's character, The Tramp?", "answer": "Kid Auto Races at Venice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babd", "question": "What team won the 2011 NBA Championship?", "answer": "Dallas Mavericks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133909c", "question": "Demeter is the goddess of what?", "answer": "Harvest and agriculture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73513eec85e375820b243", "question": "Who was President John F. Kennedy's Attorney General?", "answer": "His brother Robert F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971df3a89261e916c8e09a7", "question": "How is the groundnut better known?", "answer": "The peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a2", "question": "What is Ozzy Osbourne's real first name?", "answer": "John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b634", "question": "What company was the first to sell prepared baby food in glass jars?", "answer": "Beech-Nut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5aab2f4258d116dab4aecb48", "question": "What is racing driver's, Jean Alesi, birth name?", "answer": "Giovanni Alesi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06f", "question": "What famous ship was sunk on May 7, 1915?", "answer": "The Lusitania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb73", "question": "The card game \"Penguin\" is a variation of what other card game?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0be", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 602?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ea", "question": "On June 25, 1993, Kim Campbell became the first female prime minister of which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d08661a1c922dd1ac64c3", "question": "Hashimoto's disease is the malfunctioning of which gland?", "answer": "Thyroid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5e", "question": "What cut of beef, often used for hamburger, is also called the \"seven-bone steak\"?", "answer": "Chuck steak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb08298cf631c2414a13b46", "question": "How many soccer players should each team typically hove on the field at the start of each match?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339550", "question": "Who was Gordon Shumway?", "answer": "Alf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fa", "question": "In the movie \"The Big Lebowski\", what item did the Dude take from the Big Lebowski mansion as compensation?", "answer": "A rug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985b", "question": "In the movie \"Princess Mononoke\", what affliction do the Secret Engineers in Irontown have?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fcddfe83fe1f2a824c46", "question": "Which scientist patented new ballet shoes to protect dancers\u2019 feet?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93a7b6bd93ce3a4e5f698", "question": "Which scientific term refers to the formation of a new species?", "answer": "Speciation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e9", "question": "Pete Best and Stu Sutcliffe were past \u00admembers of what band?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27c", "question": "Who had a record song in 1963 with their cover of \"Sweets for My Sweet\"?\u00a0", "answer": "The Searchers\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971df4c89261e916c8e09a8", "question": "\"Groundnut\" is another name for what?", "answer": "The peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caaa", "question": "The cecum is the pouch at the beginning of what?", "answer": "Large intestine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b700", "question": "What sport is likely to cause pudendal nerve entrapment?", "answer": "Cycling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601737b944491cbd7c5a178d", "question": "What military leader is believed to have said, \"I can run wild for six months\u00a0... after that, I have no expectation of success\".", "answer": "Japanese Admiral\u00a0Isoroku Yamamoto -- He said this while predicting the future outcome of naval war against the U.S.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4e", "question": "The 1999 Russell Crowe film \"The Insider\" concerned a whistle-blower in what industry?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339336", "question": "What was the title of the TV series \"M*A*S*H\" theme song?", "answer": "Suicide is Painless", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5ce75dad637d903c8820", "question": "What country is nicknamed \"the land of a thousand lakes\"?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b17466cbb2d29f81593b707", "question": "Which TV detective series is set in the town of Denton?", "answer": "A Touch of Frost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ff", "question": "What was the name of the club in Liverpool made famous for the Beatles early appearances?", "answer": "The Cavern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51215ff04d658268c92cd", "question": "Who was the first American casualty in the American Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Crispus Attucks\u00a0was the first person killed in the Boston massacre and is widely considered to be the first American casualty.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf80", "question": "What is a tightrope walker called?", "answer": "Funambulist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b46506d333868d34d6e1", "question": "The east gate of Jerusalem, where Peter and John healed a lame, is known as what?", "answer": "The Beautiful Gate", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb56", "question": "What brand of whisky was created in 1939 Queen of England's visit to Canada?", "answer": "Crown Royal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb58155dad637d903c880e", "question": "Venice's famed Bridge of Sighs connects two what?", "answer": "Prisons -- The bridge connects an old prison inside the Doge's Palace to a newer one across the Rio di Palazzo.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f090ff048f679a45aa9f", "question": "Samhainophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c9", "question": "How long is a fortnight?", "answer": "Fourteen Days", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb8", "question": "Besides corn, what's the other principal ingredient in succotash?", "answer": "Lima beans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a44d", "question": "Which mountain range separates Spain from France?", "answer": "Pyrenees", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339780", "question": "The name of which Norwegian Black Metal band translates into Dark Fortress?", "answer": "Dimmu Borgir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25d", "question": "How many teats does a cow have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecd25aec223966ae8f88c4", "question": "What was the first full-length film from director Steve McQueen that did not have a one word title?", "answer": "\"12 Years a Slave\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a553423e1c6f9840ba31a2", "question": "In ancient Rome what was the \"Tabularium\"?", "answer": "\"Hall of Public Records\", or the official records office", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd8937e83c707845b2176", "question": "In what State were the exteriors of the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\" filmed?", "answer": "The exteriors of the film took place outside a soon-to-be demolished reformatory in Mansfield, Ohio.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f86cf842fa4c4ba96bc", "question": "Who is the Roman Patron Saint of hangovers?", "answer": "Saint Bibiana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e2", "question": "What year did Andre and Edouard Michelin first publish the \"Michelin Guide\"?", "answer": "1900", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaaa47e83c707845b20e0", "question": "Alektorophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Chickens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b571b6667df192a942e3368", "question": "What is the capital of Nicaragua?", "answer": "Managua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb8", "question": "What common office supply item is named for the Asian \"abaca\" fiber used to make them?", "answer": "Manila envelopes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55f", "question": "Which state is located directly to the east of Washington D.C.?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e3", "question": "Chablis is the northernmost district of what French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd9", "question": "What two-word Latin phrase means \"the reverse order\"?", "answer": "Vice versa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8f", "question": "Who invented nylon?", "answer": "Wallace Carothers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7349eeec85e375820b239", "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes was dedicated to which god?", "answer": "Helios", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcd", "question": "In bowling what is the term for knocking down all pins with 2 consecutive balls?", "answer": "A Spare\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a760", "question": "The Arc de Triumphe is to Paris, as the Brandenburg Gate is to what other European capital city?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f8", "question": "Whose novel is the basis for the Lloyd Webber musical \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Gaston Leroux's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbe", "question": "What fairytale girl eats the window pane of the witch's cottage?", "answer": "Gretel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a041", "question": "Kevin Spacey plays Francis Underwood in what Netflix original series?", "answer": "House of Cards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fed2be1ec223966ae8f8914", "question": "Who wrote The Monkees' #1 hit \"I'm a Believer\"?", "answer": "Neil Diamond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a1", "question": "What country is named for the founder of the \"Friars Preachers\" religious order?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e94d17ccba3ffe45786d8", "question": "What year did the programming language \"COBOL\" first appear, before being standardized in 1968?", "answer": "1959", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a140", "question": "In what film does Steve McQueen get to race a Mustang round the streets of San Francisco?", "answer": "Bullitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e35", "question": "Who is Campbell Scott's mother?", "answer": "Colleen Dewhurst", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f8c601dd7bf43be5e848", "question": "Who said, \"I don't make jokes. I just watch the government and report the facts\"?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c9", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f716ea9e54d890926f6e0", "question": "In which country is the Troi-Rivieres bridge?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b6", "question": "What does a \"caliber\" measure?", "answer": "The approximate internal diameter of a gun barrel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067eafff9c0647b50a807d", "question": "In 2016, who portrayed Donald Trump on the TV variety show, \"Saturday Night Live\"?", "answer": "Alec Baldwin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd7", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"R\"?", "answer": "Romeo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b013", "question": "Who was \"Time\" magazine's first \"person of the year\"?", "answer": "Charles Lindburgh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f5", "question": "In the movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\", who lost both arms and both legs in a sword fight?", "answer": "The Black Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be39", "question": "How many players are there in a standard team handball team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b594", "question": "When was the game \"Scrabble\" first released?", "answer": "1948", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94e67ccba3ffe45786da", "question": "What language was the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "FLOW-MATIC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65612ae7e414034b5aebf", "question": "The goddess Artemis was known as the Mistress of what?", "answer": "Animals", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cd8a8e347d002c297e4c8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Icarus' father?", "answer": "Daedalus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb601b5dad637d903c8829", "question": "Which city in the U.S. is home to the National Mustard Museum?", "answer": "Middleton, Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59c1cdb87bd84c0ea43ad42d", "question": "Which country borders Macedonia to the north?", "answer": "Serbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69f9120565ad31a57c78d", "question": "What sport\u2019s first non-military competition was hosted in Norway in 1868?", "answer": "Downhill skiing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590682e5ff9c0647b50a80a1", "question": "What popular mobile game, that caused many players to get into accidents, was released in July of 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon Go", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abcf", "question": "What country is home to the Bank of Alexandria?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff6685052a821ff76ae8b03", "question": "Around what sea did Jesus call His first apostles?", "answer": "Christ first saw Peter and Andrew close to the Sea of Galilee. He beseeched them to follow Him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49c", "question": "Which country was selected as a host of the 1916 Olympic Games, but didn't actually host them?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf63", "question": "How is rockstar Vincent Furnier better known?", "answer": "Alice Cooper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec7", "question": "Who was fired from the Interior Department in 1865 for having written \"Leaves of Grass\"?", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a08", "question": "For what movie did Dan Aykroyd receive an Oscar nomination?", "answer": "Driving Miss Daisy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d9", "question": "What is D.J.'s full name on the TV show \"Roseanne\"?", "answer": "David Jacob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590089e6cf842fa4c4ba968d", "question": "What was the first solo album released by Roger Waters?", "answer": "The Pros and Cons of Hitch Hiking", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e85", "question": "Who based his hit comic book character \"Dyno Woman\" on his own sister Thelma?", "answer": "J. J. Evans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c379", "question": "What name is given to male rhinoceroses?", "answer": "Bulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c3e9a84ebfabb9c85d8a97c", "question": "Which mythical creature has the body of a lion, a goat's head rising from its back and a snake's head at the tip of its tail?", "answer": "Chimaera, or Chimera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6003958357a0e35c43f83894", "question": "What is the term for reproducing a texture by laying paper over it and rubbing it with a pencil or crayon?", "answer": "Frottage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d1195b4fea7fe947a2228e", "question": "What is in the Red Data List?", "answer": "Threatened Species", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27b", "question": "Who was born Mark Feld?", "answer": "Marc Bolan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cbd7bb53d1af658864dc", "question": "What holiday is celebrated on December 26th in Canada?", "answer": "Boxing Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d119ee4fea7fe947a22292", "question": "On the Fahrenheit scale, there are 180 degrees between which two important points?", "answer": "Freezing and boiling points", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8c23ec223966ae8f8846", "question": "In 2000, which artist(s) tied Michael Jackson's 1984 record of winning eight Grammys in a single year?", "answer": "Santana (won eight Grammy Awards in 2000, tying the record set by Michael Jackson)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c505", "question": "What is a group of apes called?", "answer": "A shrewdness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b832", "question": "What would a sommelier recommend to you?", "answer": "Wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049a0bcf93664eb1048697", "question": "The Queensland nut is another name for what nut?", "answer": "Macadamia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59bb287ac9bff04efae6d750", "question": "Who wrote the book on which the Oscar winning film \"The Godfather\" was based?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ffb733a3a814d89068c65", "question": "Who wanted you to \"Shake Your Groove Thing\"?", "answer": "Peaches & Herb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af13", "question": "What city hosted the Winter Olympics in 1932?", "answer": "Lake Placid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c7830775fa611bce67da", "question": "How long is the length of an adult male tiger?", "answer": "8 to 10 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c113", "question": "What Canadian city was figure skater, Elvis Stojko, born in?", "answer": "Newmarket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab50", "question": "What is the capital of Slovenia?", "answer": "Ljubljana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f1", "question": "What is Ray Charles' real last name?", "answer": "Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7a", "question": "What word describes a cut of steak containing both the T-\u00adbone and the tenderloin?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590679b5ff9c0647b50a8051", "question": "On January 1, 2016, which Canadian province became the first one to allow the testing of self-driving vehicles on public roads?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339757", "question": "Who wrote My Girl, the hit song performed by the Temptations?", "answer": "Smokey Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0de0dfcbed638185eaa11", "question": "What was the most-visited attraction in the UK in 2017?", "answer": "British Museum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339590", "question": "What movie starring Bruce Willis contains the line \"I see dead people\"?", "answer": "The Sixth Sense", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37e", "question": "The duck-billed platypus is one of only three mammals in the world that can do what?", "answer": "Lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba395874c93a3298b213d", "question": "Who was nicknamed La Pucelle d'Orl\u00e9ans?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd6", "question": "What band was the only rap band to perform at Live Aid in 1985?", "answer": "Run D.M.C.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dfe", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"Love Will Tear Us Apart\"?", "answer": "Ian Curtis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3236bdbf195a31e15d73be", "question": "\"Oliver's Story\" was the sequel to which best-seller by Erich Segal?", "answer": "Love Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d1", "question": "The song \"A Dream Is a Wish Your Heart Makes\" was originally featured in what Disney film?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d84", "question": "What time-travel film was shot on Michigan's three-mile-long Mackinac Island?", "answer": "Somewhere in Time", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a8b0cb8751d53e7d75fe", "question": "Who won Super Bowl IV?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a1", "question": "How tall was the model ape used in the making of the movie \"King Kong\"?", "answer": "18 inches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b867", "question": "In which sport do you \"shag\" flies?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa49c6ce05a3942286eb5", "question": "The Stay Puff Marshmallow Man originally appeared in which film?", "answer": "Ghostbusters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c659", "question": "Which ape's name means \"man of the forest\"?", "answer": "Orangutan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe939926bd93ce3a4e5f68e", "question": "What term describes the amount of light a planetary body reflects?", "answer": "Albedo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590679e4ff9c0647b50a8052", "question": "What network was primarily responsible for leaking over 11.5 million documents, collectively known as the Panama Papers, on April 3, 2016?", "answer": "The International Consortium of Investigative Journalists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f6", "question": "St. Croix, St. John and St. Thomas are part of what US territory?", "answer": "Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339339", "question": "What actress played the role of Pamela Barnes Ewing on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Victoria Principal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8e", "question": "What form of writing is literally translated to \"sacred writings\"?", "answer": "Hieroglyphics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0f", "question": "Who was the only woman to hold the title office in the \"Book of Judges\"?", "answer": "Deborah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb32", "question": "What supermodel appeared dressed as George Washington on the cover of the premiere issue of \"George\" magazine?", "answer": "Cindy Crawford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e17bfe83fe1f2a824b94", "question": "What major mistake did the Allies make in preparing to defend against Germany\u2019s attack on France?", "answer": "They misinterpreted where the main invasion would take place", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdff59f1cf6db9ac4808ceb", "question": "Which U.S. territory is the country\u2019s southernmost point?", "answer": "American Samoa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cd40be1685cf15b733e988c", "question": "Which cartoon family lives in 742 Evergreen Terrace, Springfield, USA?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd9", "question": "What was the only place Tandy's popular TRS-80 computers were sold?", "answer": "RadioShack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523bff736d4be723796b33", "question": "On what day does Canada celebrate its birthday?", "answer": "July 1", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b3", "question": "What city did the Solomons call home in the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "Rutherford, Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99b5121a8909e5c332d2a", "question": "Which private investigator tried to find out who framed Roger Rabbit?", "answer": "Eddie Valiant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b38106d333868d34d6d8", "question": "Who introduced potatoes into Ireland?", "answer": "Sir Walter Raleigh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad09", "question": "What was Albert Einstein's first job after graduating from Zurich Polytechnic?", "answer": "Patent clerk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898a", "question": "Which Dickens character asked for more?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65e2b1f3c0ead6880d627", "question": "Who developed world's first color e-book reader?", "answer": "Fujitsu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d5", "question": "How many yards are there in a chain?", "answer": "22", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b36f751c3f17ccc40c8e0e", "question": "In the film \"The Sixth Sense\", what does Cole find in the box Kyra directed him to?", "answer": "A videotape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2e2258d116dab4aecb3a", "question": "As what was Taiwan formerly known?", "answer": "Formosa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa3ce6ce05a3942286eaa", "question": "Which of the Beach Boys actually knew how to surf?", "answer": "Dennis Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9de", "question": "Bubble Wrap was invented while researchers were trying to make what?", "answer": "Wallpaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e8", "question": "What martial art has a name beginning with \"K\" that means empty hand?", "answer": "Karate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbc933e60f0007efaba0e5b", "question": "What is the name of Hopalong Cassidy's horse?", "answer": "Topper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c804", "question": "What has two poles as a result of Amperian currents?", "answer": "A magnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce6", "question": "What Victor Hugo title character was enamored with a poor gypsy girl named Esmerelda?", "answer": "Quasimodo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ec", "question": "How many US states end with the letter \"O\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}]